# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

#### **PRATYUSH KUMAR**

Contact Number: 7562887639,7319320614

pratyushbits@gmail.com

## **Objective**

I am seeking a challenging position in a well-established firm, where I can improve myself, my skills and utilize my well founded work ethics, so as to have in the growth of my career.

## Career Overview

**EPC projects Management** 

Erection, Loop checking & Commissioning of Power plants Quality Assurance Bachelor of Engineering in "Instrumentation and control" Engineering with 3 year experience in erection, loop checking, commissioning and troubleshooting of instrumentation and control system for power plants confirming quality assurance. And also 2 year experience as a "Site Engineer" in Erection and Commissioning fields in thermal power plants.

## **Areas of Expertise**

- Current Employee: m/s Pooja Electricals under "ABB India Itd".
- Company Profile: Engineering, supply, installation & Commissioning of Electrical, Instrumentation & Automation control Systems.
- ❖ Projects :-
- ❖ 1. India power corporation limited, Haldia(West Bengal) Working on 3x150mw thermal power plant.

Duration: -04.09.2015 to till date

Designation: Site Engineer.

❖ 2. TALWANDI SABO POWER LTD, BANAWALI, MANSA(PUNJAB) Working on 3x660mw Thermal power station. Duration: - 05.05.2014 to 10.08.2015

Designation: Erection & Commissioning Engineer.

❖ 3. RSTEPL, Dhursar, Pokhran (Rajasthan).

Worked on 1x125 mw Concentrated Solar Thermal Power

Duration :- 07.12.2013 to 30.04.2014,

Designation: Erection & Commissioning Engineer.

❖ 4. Torrent Power Limited, Ahmadabad.

Uprating of 2x120mw Thermal Power Station.

Duration :- 02.11.2012 to .30.11.2013

Designation: Instrumentation Engineer.

❖ Job Profile :- Hands on Experience in Erection & Commissioning of

- DCS System- ABB Symphony Plus, I/O Remote Panel.
- Marshaling Panels-Interpanel wiring, cabling, termination and loop check.
- Field Instrumentation: Field Instrument Enclosures (FIE),
  Local Instrument Rack (LIR) Field Instruments: RTD,
  Thermocouple, Pressure Switch, ABB and ROSMOUNT
  make -Smart transmitter for measuring Level, pressure,
  Flow and differential pressure, belt sway switches and pull
  chord switches.
- Installation of hydratect 2462 level switches make mobrey for detection of steam and water.
- Control Valves: Installation & Calibration of Keltron, IL, Control valve actuators and Rotork actuators.
- Electrical Erection: Panel Erection, Interpanel
  Wiring, Motor Erection, DG Set Erection, LPBS
  Erection, Earthing work of Motor, Panel and Cable
  Tray, Cable Tray Erection, Transformer Erection, HT
  and LT Panel Erection, Control Panel Erection, HT
  and LT Cable laying, Cable Termination, SPBD and
  NSPBD Erection and also all type of electricals
  equipments work related Erection and
  Commissioning fields in thermal power plants.

## **ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS:**

- "Instrumentation and control" with 67.50%, in 2011 from RGTU, Bhopal. (MP)
  - ❖ Knowledge of hardware, operating systems, application programming. Windows XP, 2000.Window-7, Microsoft word and Microsoft office Excel.

### **PERSONEL SYNOPSIS:**

Father's Name : Mr. Kishor Upadhyay

Date of Birth : 20/08/1987

Nationality : Indian Marital Status : Single

Languages Known : English and Hindi.

Permanent Address : Vill.+Post- Khajuria, Via-Barauli,

Dist- Gopalgang(Bihar)

#### **DECLARATION:**

I here by declare that above mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness above mentioned particulars.

**DATE:** 

PLACE: PRATYUSH KUMAR